Alieu Gilbert Fullah



Email Address: gilbertfullah@hotmail.com / gilbertfullah@gmail.com

Phone Number: +23234727215 / +23276901488

Current Address: 16 Old Railway Line, Devil Hole, Waterloo High-Way,

Freetown, Sierra Leone, 00232

LinkedIn:www.linkedin.com/in/gilbert-fullah-6601873b

Nationality: Sierra Leonean Age: 32 | Gender: Male Marital Status: Single

Highly driven, analytical and innovative Data Scientist with over 4 years as Network and System Administrator at Bollore Transport and Logistics Freetown Sierra Leone. Recognized consistently for performance excellence and contributions to success in the network infrastructure of Bollore Transport and Logistics. I have been privileged to gain experience both locally and internationally by working at Wicresoft Shanghai China branch as a Technical Support Engineer for the Microsoft Teams product and UNDP Smart Infrastructure and Connectivity Unit in Copenhagen Denmark as an ICT Support Engineer. I was also a Lecturer at the University of Lunsar, Lunsar, Sierra Leone for 1 year, before now working as a Data Scientist for Institute for Governance Reform (IGR).

Skills

Python, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Power BI, Excel, KoboCollect, SurveyToGo Studio, Data Analysis with Python using Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn and Plotly, Machine Learning with Scikit-Learn, Deep Learning in the Natural Language Processing (NLP) area, Website development using Django, configuration, troubleshooting and deployment of Cisco networking devices, Windows Servers.

Work History

2014-06 - 2018-08

Network Administrator

Bollore Transport and Logistics, Freetown Sierra Leone

- Monitoring the overall company network system in Sierra Leone.
- Configuring routers, switches, PCs used daily by the organization.
- PC maintenance and PC assistant for users at the company.
- Administering the Servers and Configuring the Active Directory system used at the company.
- System administrator, administering the overall system of the company.

2020-08 – 2021-06 Technical Support Engineer

Wicresoft Shanghai China Branch

- Troubleshooting customer problems relating to Microsoft Teams.
- Solving customer problems relating to Microsoft Teams.
- Prepare accurate and timely reports.

2021-07 - 2021-12

ICT Support Engineer

UNDP (SICU) Unit, Copenhagen Denmark

- Solving network and connectivity problems around UNDP offices around the world.
- Working on IoT devices such as smart healthcare project were I
 gather data from the sensors, analyze, visualize and do prediction to
 help better optimize the use of IoT deployment on UNDP offices and
 countries.

2021-07 - 2022-05

Lecturer

University of Lunsar, Lunsar, Sierra Leone.

- Conducting lectures on ICT for students in the Nursing and Engineering departments.
- Develop, architect and implement the network infrastructure of the University of Lunsar.
- University of Lunsar Information Technology administrator for network, learning platform and medical center.

2022-06 - Present

Data Analyst

Institute for Governance Reform (IGR), Freetown, Sierra Leone

- Data Monitoring, cleaning and analysis using different tools such as Excel, Python and Power BI.
- Survey questionnaire development using KoboCollect and SurveyToGo.
- Collaborate with IGR staffs on different programs relating to data.

Education

2018-09 – 2020-08	Master of Science: Information and Communication Engineering Huazhong University of Science and Technology - Wuhan, Hubei, China
2009-10 - 2013-07	Bachelor of Science: Information Systems
	University of Sierra Leone - Freetown, Sierra Leone

Projects

- Hate speech detection and analysis on Facebook comments
- Developed Sierra Leone Labour Market Information System (LMIS)
- Topic and Sentiment Analysis on Belt and Road Initiative Using News Articles in Kenya and China Media.
- Smart Healthcare System in Uganda using IoT devices.
- Afrobarometer Round 9 Survey for Sierra Leone.
- Did Surveys and data analysis projects for World Bank, Irish Aid and CARL.